<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on Rahul Bajaj</title>
    <link>https://journalctl.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on Rahul Bajaj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:00:59 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://journalctl.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Slimming Down Containers: The Art of Minimizing Image Bloat</title>
      <link>https://journalctl.com/post/lean-container-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:00:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journalctl.com/post/lean-container-images/</guid>
      <description>OpenShift, an enterprise-ready Kubernetes platform, offers a multitude of benefits. One such advantage is the Source-to-Image (S2I) build strategy, that simplifies the process of converting source code into deployable container images. This strategy enables developers to build container images without the need to define a container file explicitly. OpenShift clones the application&amp;rsquo;s source code into a builder image that utilizes builder scripts, ultimately generating a container image deployable within the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Containers with Systemd</title>
      <link>https://journalctl.com/post/systemd-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 15:02:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journalctl.com/post/systemd-containers/</guid>
      <description>Containers are inherently ephemeral, making them more difficult to manage than traditional programmes operating on virtual or bare metal servers. Container monitoring, on the other hand, is a critical capability for applications based on current microservices architectures in order to achieve maximum performance.
Containerized applications frequently necessitate monitoring. Performing health-checks is one technique to keep these containers up and running at all times. The usage of the curl command to verify if the application within the container is still up and running is one of the approaches I&amp;rsquo;ve come across for doing health-checks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving into the Open Source Ocean: A Recap of the Summit&#39;s Key Moments</title>
      <link>https://journalctl.com/post/ossna2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 08:59:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journalctl.com/post/ossna2023/</guid>
      <description>From May 10th to 12th, the Vancouver Convention Center came alive with the Open Source Summit North America, a three-day event that brought together open source software enthusiasts from around the world. With a focus on exploring the newest trends and embracing opportunities in the ever-changing field of open source technology, this premier conference drew over two thousand attendees. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into my own presentation and its key points, share some highlights from the inspiring talks I attended, and take a closer look at the exciting conversations and new discoveries that unfolded at the Red Hat booth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
